<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<mdRecord 
            xmlns='http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu'
            xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance'
            xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'
            xmlns:dcterms='http://purl.org/dc/terms/'
            xmlns:rdf='http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#'
            xmlns:edm='http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/'
            xsi:schemaLocation='http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu dplava.xsd'
          >
	<dcterms:identifier>evans_00051</dcterms:identifier>
	<dcterms:isPartOf>Evans, George Bird. Papers</dcterms:isPartOf>
	<dcterms:title>Shooting Notes</dcterms:title>
	<dcterms:created>1981</dcterms:created>
	<dcterms:creator>Evans, George Bird</dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:description>In this journal, George notes that it is his 57th season and his dog Belton's 6th season. Belton is 5 years and 5 months old. Noting that this season is particularly bad for grouse hunting in West Virginia, George makes his way to New York State, where he hunts in locations including the Smithville Flats, Pharsalia, Hunt Road, Melondy Hill, Harford, the German Corners, and Plank Road. In West Virginia and Pennsylvania, he hunts for grouse and woodcock in locations in and around Mt. Storm, Clyde Davis's land, Bayard Cemetery Ridge, Rifle Ridge, Grassy Ridge, Aurora, the Gates, Donald Mover's thorns, Hog Run West, Cranesville, Hartman, Morrison, Maust, Matthews, Tarleton, Lower Hog Run, and Graveyard Glade. He praises Belton's skills for flushing woodcock, though later he notes that the dog is giving him problems by going to grouse for scent, a habit picked up from woodcock hunting. He notes the thick rhododendron and hawthorn cover. On his outings, he remembers hunting with Briar fondly, and reminisces about Belton's first point at a quail. His wife, Kay, often accomanies George on his outings. His journals include tables of hunt statistics for each location, as well as hunt numbers for himself and Belton.</dcterms:description>
	<dcterms:subject>Dogs</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Evans, George Bird</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Hunters</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Hunting</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Hunting dogs </dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Preston County</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Shooting</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>West Virginia</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
	<dcterms:provenance>West Virginia University Libraries</dcterms:provenance>
	<edm:isShownAt>http://gbe.lib.wvu.edu/record/evans_00051</edm:isShownAt>
	<edm:preview>http://gbe.lib.wvu.edu/imageviewer/evans_00051/image</edm:preview>
</mdRecord>
