<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<mdRecord 
            xmlns='http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu'
            xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance'
            xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'
            xmlns:dcterms='http://purl.org/dc/terms/'
            xmlns:rdf='http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#'
            xmlns:edm='http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/'
            xsi:schemaLocation='http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu dplava.xsd'
          >
	<dcterms:identifier>evans_00049</dcterms:identifier>
	<dcterms:isPartOf>Evans, George Bird. Papers</dcterms:isPartOf>
	<dcterms:title>Shooting Notes</dcterms:title>
	<dcterms:created>1979</dcterms:created>
	<dcterms:creator>Evans, George Bird</dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:description>With sadness, George begins his journal noting that is his first year hunting without Briar after ten seasons together, and that both he and Kay consider Briar to have been one of their finest setters. Belton, however, is living up to high expectations, with George greatly enjoying their outings together. Accompanied by Belton and Kay, George details his outings in each entry, noting the time, weather, and location. This year, he finds trapping prevalent due to the high price for pelts, and hopes it will curb predators. George, Kay, and Briar hunt for grouse adn woodcock in and around Graveyard Glade, Ft. Morris Thorns, Cherry Grove, Morrison, Plum Place, Cupp Place, Falkenstine, Lower Shafer, Hoyes Run, Seese Place, Mountaindale, Tucker Place, Webb Chapel, Radabaugh, Little Sandy, Hog Run, Eisentrout, Stony River Gap, Ridge Road South, Ridge Road North, the Gates, Rehobeth Thorns, Two-Grouse Run, Grassy Ridge, Edelman, Pigeon Roost, and Ohio. He includes tables with hunt statistics for each location and for Belton.</dcterms:description>
	<dcterms:subject>Dogs</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Evans, George Bird</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Hunters</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Hunting</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Hunting dogs </dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Preston County</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Shooting</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>West Virginia</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
	<dcterms:provenance>West Virginia University Libraries</dcterms:provenance>
	<edm:isShownAt>http://gbe.lib.wvu.edu/record/evans_00049</edm:isShownAt>
	<edm:preview>http://gbe.lib.wvu.edu/imageviewer/evans_00049/image</edm:preview>
</mdRecord>
