<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<mdRecord 
            xmlns='http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu'
            xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance'
            xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'
            xmlns:dcterms='http://purl.org/dc/terms/'
            xmlns:rdf='http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#'
            xmlns:edm='http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/'
            xsi:schemaLocation='http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu dplava.xsd'
          >
	<dcterms:identifier>evans_00052</dcterms:identifier>
	<dcterms:isPartOf>Evans, George Bird. Papers</dcterms:isPartOf>
	<dcterms:title>Shooting Notes</dcterms:title>
	<dcterms:created>1982</dcterms:created>
	<dcterms:creator>Evans, George Bird</dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:description>Now in his 58th season, George does not hunt on Opening Day. When he does hunt, however, he is accompanied by his dog, Belton, and his wife, Kay. He meets with friends including Clarence Friend, John Landis, and Neil Sheehan. Throughout the season, he hunts in locations in and around Al Brown's place, the Friends' land, Dolly Sods, Fisher's Spring Bog, Somerville Road, the Allegheny Mountains, Ben Thompson's "gates," Mount Storm South, the Hartman Place, Blackwater Falls, Canaan Valley, Paul Uphold's land, Pigeon Roost Road, Poplar house, Rehobeth, Graveyard Glade, the Matthews' Place, Spruce Spring, Three States Corners, Galecrest, Upper Wilderness, Little Sandy North, Tub Run, Far Cucumber Run, Parnell Road, Meyers Rocks, and the Wilkinson Place. In each entry, he notes the location, weather, and makes some notes regarding the performance of Belton. He notes the thick hawthorne, blackberry, and grapevine cover, and admires the fields of goldenrod and St. Johns Wort. He sees hawks, groundhogs, and owls, but finds the grouse lacking. During Thanksgiving, he hunts along the Mason-Dixon line. He hunts with Kay on their 56th anniversary. Unlike many of his other journals, he does not include tables of statistics for each hunt location.</dcterms:description>
	<dcterms:subject>Dogs</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Evans, George Bird</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Hunters</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Hunting</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Hunting dogs </dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Preston County</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Shooting</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>West Virginia</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
	<dcterms:provenance>West Virginia University Libraries</dcterms:provenance>
	<edm:isShownAt>http://gbe.lib.wvu.edu/record/evans_00052</edm:isShownAt>
	<edm:preview>http://gbe.lib.wvu.edu/imageviewer/evans_00052/image</edm:preview>
</mdRecord>
