<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<mdRecord 
            xmlns='http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu'
            xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance'
            xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'
            xmlns:dcterms='http://purl.org/dc/terms/'
            xmlns:rdf='http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#'
            xmlns:edm='http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/'
            xsi:schemaLocation='http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu dplava.xsd'
          >
	<dcterms:identifier>evans_00058</dcterms:identifier>
	<dcterms:isPartOf>Evans, George Bird. Papers</dcterms:isPartOf>
	<dcterms:title>Shooting Notes</dcterms:title>
	<dcterms:created>1988-07-16</dcterms:created>
	<dcterms:creator>Evans, George Bird</dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:description>It is George's 64th season gunning grouse. This year finds George at 81 3/4 years old, while Belton is 12 1/2 and Quest is 4 1/2. Belton starts chemotherapy, and while initially he seems to be doing well, George soon realizes that he cannot hunt as he normally does, as he tires easily. George eventually makes a note of Belton's last day hunting. George, Kay, and the dogs go hunting on and around locations including Ray Guthrie's land, the hartman place, Clyde Davis' land, Canaan Valley, Mt. Storm, Rehobeth Thorns, Poplar House, Hank Mullen's land, Black Bear Woods, Hank Mallow's land, Canaan Mountain, the Corinth thorns, Paul Uphold's land, Greene County, Deer Lake, the Asa Wright house, Ray Guthrie's land, and Little Sandy North. He meets up with friends Jimmy Spiker and Mrs. Ward Crane. George refers to this year as a "lost season," noting Belton's poor health and his own re-injuring of his right shoulder, which makes it impossible for him to shoot. With frustration, he writes that he moved around twenty grouse this season in West Virginia, the same number he would havemoved in the '40's and '50's in a single day. George includes a table of statistics with organized data for his hunt locations and dogs. </dcterms:description>
	<dcterms:subject>Dogs</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Evans, George Bird</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Hunters</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Hunting</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Hunting dogs </dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Preston County</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Shooting</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>West Virginia</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/UND/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
	<dcterms:provenance>West Virginia University Libraries</dcterms:provenance>
	<edm:isShownAt>http://gbe.lib.wvu.edu/record/evans_00058</edm:isShownAt>
	<edm:preview>http://gbe.lib.wvu.edu/imageviewer/evans_00058/image</edm:preview>
</mdRecord>
