<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<mdRecord 
          xmlns='http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu'
          xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance'
          xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'
          xmlns:dcterms='http://purl.org/dc/terms/'
          xmlns:rdf='http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#'
          xmlns:edm='http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/'
          xsi:schemaLocation='http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu dplava.xsd'
        >
	<dcterms:identifier>ptp_1054</dcterms:identifier>
	<dcterms:isPartOf>Francis H. Pierpont Civil War Telegrams</dcterms:isPartOf>
	<dcterms:title>Stanton, Edwin M.  to Pierpont, Francis H.</dcterms:title>
	<dcterms:created>1865-04-09</dcterms:created>
	<dcterms:creator>Stanton, Edwin M. </dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:description>9 p.m.
Alexa[ndria] April 9 1865
By Telegraph from War Dept. 9 1865
This department has just recd official report of the surrender this day of Genl Lee and his army to Lt. Genl Grant on the terms proposed by Genl Grant Details will be given speedily as possible.
Edwin M. Stanton 
Secy of War 

Head Qrs Army of U.S.
430 Rm
Hon. E.M. Stanton Secy of War
Genl Lee surrendered the Army of Northern Virginia this afternoon upon terms [page 2] proposed by myself.  The accompanying additional correspondence will show the conditions fully
U.S. Grant
Lt. Genl

Apl 9 1865
Genl-
I recd your note of this morning on the picket line whither I had come to meet you to ascertain definitely what terms were embraced in your presentation of yesterday with reference to the surrender of this army. [page 3] I now request an interview in accordance with offer contained in your letter of yesterday - for that purpose.
Very Respy
Your Off
R.E. Lee 
Genl CSA

to U.S. Grant
Comder US Army

[page 4]

Apl 9 1865
Genl R.E. Lee
Comdr CSA

Your note of this date is but this moment (1158 am) recd in consequence of having passed from the Richmond [crossed out] and Lynchburg road to the Farquiville and Lynchburg road I am at this writing about four miles west  of Walters Church and will push forward to the front of the purpose of meeting - notice sent to me on this road where you wish the interview to take place will meet me -
Very respy your Off
Genl U.S. Grant

[page 5]

Appomattox CH Apl 9
1865
Genl R.E. Lee
Comdr CSA
In accordance with the substance of my letter to you of the 8th inst. I propose to receive the surrender of the Army of Northern Va on the following terms to wit Rolls of the all officers and men to be made in duplicate - 
One copy to be given to an officer designated by me the others to be retained by such officer or officers do you may designate - the officers to give [page 6] their individual paroles not to carry arms against the Govt of the United States until property exchanged and each Co or Regt commander sign a like parole for the men of their commands - The Army's artillery and public property to be packed and stacked and turned over to the officers appointed by me to receive them - This will not embrace the side arms of the officers nor their private horses or baggage - This done - such officers and men will be allowed - to return to their homes not to be disturbed by United States [page 7] authority so long as they observe their parole and the laws in force where they may reside - 
Very Respy
U.S. Grant
Lt. Genl

Hd Qrs Army Northern Va
9th Apl 1865
Lt General U.S. Grant
Comdr USA

Genl
I have recd your letter of this date containing the terms of surrender of Army of Northern Virginia as proposed by you - as they are substantially the same as those proposed in your [page 8] letter of the 8th Inst they are accepted. I will proceed to designate the proper officers to carry the stipulations into effect.
Very Respy
Your Off
R.E. Lee
Lt. Genl
</dcterms:description>
	<dcterms:extent>page 7 of 8; leaf 7 of 8</dcterms:extent>
	<dcterms:subject>Stanton, Edwin M. </dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Alexandria. Virginia</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>no location given</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Pierpont, Francis H.</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:spatial>Alexandria. Virginia</dcterms:spatial>
	<dcterms:spatial>no location given</dcterms:spatial>
	<dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
	<dcterms:provenance>West Virginia University Libraries</dcterms:provenance>
	<edm:isShownAt>https://civilwarwv.lib.wvu.edu/record/ptp_1054</edm:isShownAt>
	<edm:preview>https://civilwarwv.lib.wvu.edu/image/ptp_1054.jpg</edm:preview>
</mdRecord>
