<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<mdRecord 
          xmlns='http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu'
          xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance'
          xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'
          xmlns:dcterms='http://purl.org/dc/terms/'
          xmlns:rdf='http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#'
          xmlns:edm='http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/'
          xsi:schemaLocation='http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu dplava.xsd'
        >
	<dcterms:identifier>ptp_0464</dcterms:identifier>
	<dcterms:isPartOf>Francis H. Pierpont Civil War Telegrams</dcterms:isPartOf>
	<dcterms:created>1861-11-04</dcterms:created>
	<dcterms:creator>Hill, Isaiah S.</dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:description>His Excy Gov Peirpoint [Francis H. Pierpont] Wheeling Nov 4 1861.  By Telegraph from Camp Peirpoint  Wirt Co Nov 3 1861.   We have been ordered from this place to Clarksburg forthwith and are preparing to obey the same.  this order has produced the most intense excitement in this town &amp; vicinity so much so that a large portion of the best citizens of the town &amp; county around are preparing to leave the county because they feel that neither their persons or property are safe a single day in the absence of the troops even the sheriff himself is preparing to leave.  If either of my subalterns or any one else have reported to you or any of the military departments that there is nothing for us to do here I take it upon myself most unequivocally to say that it is false we have more work now before us at this particular time than we have ever had before this town is threatened more particularly now if the troops should leave than heretofore &amp; those threats will most assuredly be carried out so soon as we [page 2] leave we have been in active[crossed out] active service from the twenty fourth of June &amp; have not received one dime in the way of pay we also need our clothing &amp; horses to be efficient in the service if we are to remain here the citizens are opposed to our removal yet so far as I am concerned I am perfectly willing to serve my country wherever I am so called I.S. Hill Capt 1st Va. C. 239.727paid</dcterms:description>
	<dcterms:extent>page 2 of 2; leaf 1 of 1</dcterms:extent>
	<dcterms:subject>Hill, Isaiah S.</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Camp Peirpoint, Wirt County</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Wheeling, (West) Virginia</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Pierpont, Francis Harrison</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:spatial>Camp Peirpoint, Wirt County</dcterms:spatial>
	<dcterms:spatial>Wheeling, (West) Virginia</dcterms:spatial>
	<dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
	<dcterms:provenance>West Virginia University Libraries</dcterms:provenance>
	<edm:isShownAt>https://civilwarwv.lib.wvu.edu/record/ptp_0464</edm:isShownAt>
	<edm:preview>https://civilwarwv.lib.wvu.edu/image/ptp_0464.jpg</edm:preview>
</mdRecord>
