<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<mdRecord 
          xmlns='http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu'
          xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance'
          xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'
          xmlns:dcterms='http://purl.org/dc/terms/'
          xmlns:rdf='http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#'
          xmlns:edm='http://www.europeana.eu/schemas/edm/'
          xsi:schemaLocation='http://dplava.lib.virginia.edu dplava.xsd'
        >
	<dcterms:identifier>ptp_0948</dcterms:identifier>
	<dcterms:isPartOf>Francis H. Pierpont Civil War Telegrams</dcterms:isPartOf>
	<dcterms:created>1863-04-20</dcterms:created>
	<dcterms:creator>Lincoln, Abraham</dcterms:creator>
	<dcterms:description>By the President of the United States of America. A Proclamation. Whereas, by the Act of Congress approved the 31st day of December, last, the State of West Virginia was declared to be one of the United States of America, and was admitted into the Union on an equal footing with the original states in all respects whatever, upon the condition that certain changes should be duly made in the proposed Constitution for that state;  And, Whereas, proof of a compliance with that condition as required by the Second Section of the Act aforesaid, has been submitted to me;  Now, therefore, be it known, that I, Abraham Lincoln, President of the United States, do, hereby, in pursuance of the Act of Congress aforesaid, declare and proclaim that the said act shall take effect and be in force, from and after sixty days from the date hereof.  In witness whereof, I have hereunder set my hand [page 2] and caused the Seal of the United States to be affixed.  Done at the city of Washington, this twentieth day of April, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and sixty-three, and of the Independence of the United States to eighty-seventh.  Abraham Lincoln. By the President; William H. Seward, Secretary of State.
</dcterms:description>
	<dcterms:extent>page 2 of 2; leaf 2 of 2</dcterms:extent>
	<dcterms:subject>Lincoln, Abraham</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>Washington, D.C.</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>no location given</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:subject>no recipient given</dcterms:subject>
	<dcterms:spatial>Washington, D.C.</dcterms:spatial>
	<dcterms:spatial>no location given</dcterms:spatial>
	<dcterms:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dcterms:rights>
	<dcterms:provenance>West Virginia University Libraries</dcterms:provenance>
	<edm:isShownAt>https://civilwarwv.lib.wvu.edu/record/ptp_0948</edm:isShownAt>
	<edm:preview>https://civilwarwv.lib.wvu.edu/image/ptp_0948.jpg</edm:preview>
</mdRecord>
